Inventory of the Laurence L. Wilson collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Laurence L. Wilson collection
1942-1946
45016
Wilson, Laurence L., collector.
1 manuscript box, 1 oversize folder (0.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives. Stanford, California 94305-6010
Materials relating to conditions in the Japanese-occupied Philippines during World War II and the return of American troops to the Philippines, including writings, leaflets, posters, and proclamations.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1945.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Materials relating to conditions in the Japanese-occupied Philippines during World War II and the return of American troops to the Philippines, including writings, leaflets, posters, and proclamations.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
World War, 1939-1945--Philippines.; Philippines--History--Japanese occupation, 1942-1945.
Collection Contents
- Kiangan during the Japanese Occupation, compiled historical materials, 1946 (Folder 1: 1)
- Baguio during the Japanese Occupation, compiled historical materials, 1946 (Folder 1: 2)
  Includes photographs
- Malolos during the Japanese Occupation, compiled historical materials, 1946 (Folder 1: 3)
- Tagumpay, Emilio Aguinaldo presidential candidate pamphlet, September 1935 (Folder 1: 4)
- Writings on the Philippines, Japanese propaganda, and strategy, 1942, 1944-1945 (Folder 1: 5)
- Asociación de los Veteranos de la Revolución, 1943 (Folder 1: 6)
- U.S. forces in the Philippines documents, 1945 (Folder 1: 7)
- President Osmeña issuances, 1945 (Folder 1: 8)
- President Osmeña executive orders and food price lists, 1944-1945 (Folder 1: 9)
- "Welcome MacArthur" leaflets, 1945 (Folder 1: 10)
- Telephone directory, Office of Minister Sabido, undated (Folder 1: 11)
- Philippine proclamations and posters, circa 1943-1945 (Folder Oversize folder)
  Includes presidential proclamations, "Welcome MacArthur" signs, political posters, and other oversize printed materials